m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172
人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译  双语字幕
■
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.YYeTs.com
翻译：娜姬雅  暮秋雪  阿蘅阿蘅  12CC醉芝士
校对：倔强金牛赛太公  挑刺处女YY猫后期：孤帆    时间轴：加森
Dialogue: 0,0:00:29.95,0:00:32.01,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,老爸老妈浪漫史
第八季  第十七集
总监   YY
后期：孤帆    时间轴：加森
老爸老妈浪漫史
第八季  第十八集
这才是天堂般的生活
This is the life.
我们拥有美好生活的三"大"要素
We got the three B's.
大片海滩  大杯喝酒  大波美女
Beach, booze and bodacious babes.
我不确定
I don't know.
我都有点想找警察求助了
I'm starting to think we should call the police.
拜托放轻松  好吗
Oh, would you relax?
我们都搞定了
We've got it made.
他把海边大宅借我们用一个礼拜
One whole week at his bodacious beach house,
而且是无附加条件[无线]
no strings attached.
其实  有一条线
Well, there is one string attached.
嗨  巴尼
Hi, Barney.
波大滔天
Bodacious.
"巴尼家的周末"
"Weekend at Barney's!"
什么  出什么事了
What is it? What's wrong?
秘技  罗宾  我的泡妞秘技
The plays, Robin, the plays.
那些我单身时候独创的
The ingenious techniques I used as a bachelor
泡波大无脑妹的把戏
to pick up busty dullards.
在我脑中一波波袭来  我关不掉那些画面
They just keep coming to me; I can't turn them off.
没事的  巴尼  我来帮你顺顺毛
Okay, Barney, let me ease your mind, okay?
好的  来吧
All right, here we go.
记不记得你烧掉《泡妞秘笈》那天
Remember when you set your Playbook on fire?
就在那一刻  我觉得你是可以托付终生的男人
That was the moment I realized you were someone I could marry.
如果可以重来  我还是会选择烧掉它
And I'd burn it again if I could.
你说得对
You're right.
我已经厌倦那些把戏了
I'm done with all these plays.
而且  "巴尼家的周末"
Besides, there's no way I'll ever come up
是我的巅峰之作  没有什么可以超越了
with anything that tops "Weekend at Barney's."
"巴尼家的周末  第二集"
"Weekend at Barney's Two!"
去死吧  巴尼
Damn it, Barney!
今晚有个大型画展开幕
So, there's this big gallery opening tonight.
我们很乐意出席  可惜我们要去...
Oh, we'd love to, but we've got this, um...
创世纪乐队回归演唱会  在麦迪逊广场花园
Genesis reunion, Madison Square Garden,
前排座位  绝对会成为传...
front row. It's gonna be legend...
我没有要邀请你们
I wasn't inviting you guys.
谢天谢地  其实没有什么演唱会
Oh, thank God. There is no concert.
作为船长新任的艺术买手
As the captain's new art buyer,
有一个新秀艺术家叫斯特里克兰・史蒂文斯
I have to go schmooze this up-and-coming artist,
我得去跟他套套近乎
Strickland Stevens,
这样就可以近水楼台先得月了
so we get first dibs on all his new stuff.
我负责帮莉莉把买卖拿下
And I'll be helping Lily seal the deal
通过开几个与艺术沾边的玩笑
by impressing the intelligentsia
博取那个知识分子的好感
with some art-related hilarity.
所以我准备了几个笑话
I've prepared some jokes.
为什么艺术品商人付不起房租
Why couldn't the art dealer pay his rent?
-不知道  为什么  -我要听不下去了
- I don't know. Why? - This is gonna be rough.
因为"莫奈"没了
Because he ran out of Monet.
莫奈和金钱英文读音相近
你们会在回家路上琢磨出笑点的
You're gonna get that on the walk home.
再听听这个
How about this one?
我们...我们特别爱听你讲笑话
You know what, we'd... we'd love to hear it,
但是我们要去...那个...
but we've got that, um... that...
斯迪力・丹乐队  卡内基音乐厅
Steely Dan, Carnegie Hall,
后台通行证  快走
backstage pass. Let's go.
-我们可不想错过他们不知道啥的经典名曲  -对
- We don't want to miss whatever their big song was. - Yeah.
答应你们的婚礼请柬答复卡
Your wedding response card, as promised.
你为什么不跟别人一样  邮寄给我们呢
Why didn't you just mail it like everybody else?
罗宾  太伤心了
Oh, see, that's sad, Robin.
我亲手奉上  你应该感动啊
You should be touched that I hand-delivered it.
社交媒体已经把我们的人际关系侵蚀了吗
Has social media so eroded our interpersonal relationships
人们再也不想体验...
that we no longer wish to experience the...
你只是舍不得花钱买邮票
You wanted to keep the stamp?
都涨到46美分一张了
They're 46 cents now.
简直无法无天了
It's getting out of hand.
"我们很高兴接受您的邀请
"Your invitation is joyfully accepted
泰德・莫斯比和珍妮特上"
by Mr. Ted Mosby and Jeanette""
孩子们  还记得吧
Kids, as you'll recall,
珍妮特是遇见你们妈妈前
Jeanette was the last girl I dated
我交的最后一个女朋友
before I met your mother.
我的朋友们对她  只有一点不满
My friends only had one tiny problem with her.
她是疯子
She was nuts.
所以你要带女伴参加啊
So you're bringing a plus one?
如果算上她的分裂人格
If you count the voices in her head,
其实带了五个女伴
it's plus five.
大伙  我会带她出席
Guys, I'm bringing her,
而且你们一定和她相处得很愉快
and you're gonna love having her there.
对了  顺便说一句
Oh, and, um, by the way,
有件事希望你们不要有意见
just so this doesn't turn into an argument later,
她那天会穿白礼服
the dress she's gonna wear
严格说不是纯白色  是米白色
isn't technically white; it's eggshell.
不过  她会穿纯白的鞋子
The shoes are white, though.
戴纯白的手套
And the gloves.
还有面纱  就这样  拜拜
And the veil. Well, see you guys.
别走  别走  莫斯比
No, no, no. Mosby! Get...
我的天啊  发生什么事了
Oh, my God, what happened?
我刚砸了你的公寓
Oh, I trashed your apartment.
我刚才有点无聊
See, I got bored,
-就开始翻你的电子邮件  -好吧
- so I started going through all your E-mails. - Sure.
我发现有个女人给你
And I found one from a woman
发了一封标题为《大乓高潮》的邮件
with the subject line, "Big penis orgasms,"
所以很自然地  我砸烂你的盘子
so naturally, I smashed your plates,
划穿你的床垫  还在你抽屉里撒尿
knifed your mattress, peed in your drawers,
九个抽屉无一幸免
the whole nine, but then,
当我准备把屎拉在你马桶水箱时
while I was upper-decking your toilet,
我仔细看了一下那封邮件
I actually read the e-mail.
结果那是封垃圾邮件
Turns out it was spam.
典型的珍妮特作风  对吧
Classic Jeanette, huh?
老天啊
Oh, my God.
你绝对是病理学上的疯...
You are certifiably insane...
狂爱我啊
...about me.
快过来  小傻瓜
Come here, you knucklehead.
我对你真是生不起气来
I can't stay mad at you.
泰德  泰德  我想跟你分手
Ted, Ted, I'm breaking up with you.
你总是紧张兮兮
You're just so intense,
而且我们进展太快了
and it's all moving way too fast.
钥匙还给你
Here's your key back.
我没给过你钥匙啊
I never gave you a key.
你祖母的戒指也还给你
And here's your grandmother's ring.
她不是戴着这戒指入土的吗
She was buried wearing this.
就这样  我们分手了
And just like that, it was over.
我发短信告诉巴尼和罗宾了
I texted Barney and Robin.
他们听说珍妮特不出席婚礼
I'm sure they're over the moon
肯定高兴得不得了吧
that Jeanette's not coming to the wedding.
不  泰德  不会的
Oh, no, Ted, no.
他们不会把快乐建筑在你的悲伤之上
They're not gonna be happy about you being sad.
他俩终于分手了
They broke up!
泰德  容我冒昧问一句
Ted, respectfully,
你真的觉得这女孩是你的天命真女吗
are you sure that this was the right girl for you?
绝对不是
Of course not.
她是个疯子
She was crazy.
绝对是个噩梦
Absolutely a nightmare.
完全不值得为她劳心费神
It's totally not worth the trouble.
我是说  无论如何
I mean, no matter how...
不管我们的性爱有多棒
no matter how great the sex was.
兄弟  别让精虫上脑
Stay with us, buddy.
不管场面多么热辣  多么激情四射
No matter how hot and passionate
多么奇招百出
and surprising,
或许违法了...
possibly illegal...
-我不喜欢这样  -我也是
- I don't like this. - Me, neither.
我要把她追回来
I'm gonna win her back.
巴尼和罗宾一定会为我的幸福而高兴的
Barney and Robin are gonna be so happy I'm happy.
我懂  我懂
I know. I know.
你是不是把我胸罩解开了
Did you just unhook my bra?
乖  乖
There, there.
当晚也是画展之夜
That night was the big gallery show.
真不好意思
Hey. I'm so sorry.
-我刚去杂货店买了一份零食  -为什么
- I decided to grab a snack from the bodega. - Why?
画展都会准备吃的
They'll have food at the gallery.
拜托  这些地方从来没吃的
Oh, come on, these places never have food.
没事的
It's fine.
我拿了些彩虹糖
I got some Skittles.
那是你马修叔叔
That was the last bag of Skittles
买的最后一包彩虹糖
your Uncle Marshall would ever buy.
与此同时  我为了追回珍妮特
Meanwhile, I headed over to Jeanette's place
而跑到她家
to win her back.
什么情况
What the hell?
我不能让你这么做  泰德
I can't let you do this, Ted.
-我要追回珍妮特  -不行
- I want Jeanette back. - No.
那么  请原谅我吧
Well, then accept my apology.
原谅什么
For what?
对你出手
This.
靠  你真有劲
Damn it! You're strong.
-这是练普拉提练的吗  -一周两次
- That's just from Pilates?  - Twice a week.
我不希望你和珍妮特复合
Look, I don't want you getting back with Jeanette.
泰德  我的唯一准则是什么
Ted, what is my one rule?
根据姑娘的胳膊肘判断出她的年龄吗
You can tell how old a girl is by her elbows?
另外一条
My other one rule.
用亚麻籽可以缓解腹痛
Flaxseed relieves upset stomach?
另外一条
My other one rule.
总是随身携带两张音乐会的假票
Always have a fake pair of concert tickets in your pocket
以防莉莉邀请你们去参加什么白痴活动
in case Lily invites you to something stupid?
另外一条
My other one rule.
黎巴嫩的妞都很容易上三垒  但也止步三垒
Lebanese girls sprint to third base and then stay there?
-另外一条  -旧不如新
- My other one rule. - New is always better.
旧不如新
New is always better!
太对了  泰德
Exactly, Ted.
你想要带个女伴参加我们的婚礼
You want to invite a date to our wedding,
但她不可以是珍妮特
it is not gonna be Jeanette.
得是某位新人
It is gonna be someone new.
而我将会帮你找到她
And I am gonna help you find her
只要稍稍借助于
with a little help from...
《泡妞秘笈》
The Playbook.
《泡妞秘笈》  你不是烧了吗
The Playbook? Didn't you burn that?
我又没烧那本真的
Oh, I didn't burn the real one.
烧的那本是专门搞仪式用的
That was the ceremonial playbook
比如庆祝游行  商场开业
for parades, mall openings,
就职典礼这些事情
inaugurations, stuff like that.
那可是瞒着罗宾的惊天大秘密啊
That's a pretty big secret to keep from Robin.
也正是我为什么会相信你
Which is exactly why I'm trusting you,
我最好的兄弟  永远不会告诉她
my best bro, to never let her know
《泡妞秘笈》仍然存在世上
that the Playbook still exists.
拉钩钩
Pinky swear?
好吧
Fine.
禁止携带食品
看  我跟你说了吧
See, I told you.
感谢上帝  我把这包好东西偷带进来了
Thank God I snuck in this bag of goodness.
那是斯特里克兰・史蒂文斯
There's Strickland Stevens.
就连他的围巾都让人觉得很有前途
Even his scarf is up-and-coming.
你可以自己单独待一会儿吗
Are you gonna be okay by yourself for a few minutes?
当然可以  有什么不可以
Yeah, of course. Why wouldn't I be?
因为你坐着的一件价值8万美元的雕塑
Well, you're sitting on an $80,000 sculpture.
这要8万美元啊
For 80 grand,
这价钱还以为能坐起来更舒服呢
you'd think it would be more comfortable.
莉莉  我没事的
Lil, I'll be fine.
你知道自己在跟谁说话吗
Do you know who you're talking to?
在美国有些高中学制为四年
在高中  我高一  高三  高四
In high school, I was voted most outgoing
都被选为最会交际的人
freshman, sophomore and senior year.
高二那年怎么没选上
What happened junior year?
艾杜德・法兰克
Egdud Ferhaki,
那个超爱交际的贱人
that outgoing son of a bitch.
他打败你获得了最佳交际奖吗
He beat you for most outgoing?
没有  我们并列了
Huh? Oh, no, we tied.
96年度最佳交际奖
艾杜德・法兰克和马修・埃里克森
两人并列获得
重点是我能在任何地方交朋友  即便是这里
Look, the point is, I can make friends anywhere, even here.
-谢谢你  宝贝  -没问题
- Thanks, baby. - You got it.
你好  打扰了
Hey, excuse me.
听着
Listen.
你觉得你会不会喜欢一档
Do you think that you would enjoy a show
主要介绍多纳泰罗  拉斐尔
featuring Donatello, Raphael,
米开朗基罗和达芬奇的节目呢
Michelangelo and Leonardo?
忍者神龟是以这四位伟大艺术家的名字而命名的
看来你确实是
Sound like you're a fan
忍者神龟的粉丝啊
of the Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles.
Skin it是不敬的印度俚语  意为"手淫"
骗到你了吧  击下掌
Gotcha. Skin it.
他开车回家路上会琢磨出笑点的
He will get that on the drive home.
他没有
He didn't.
-烟花  -没错
- Fireworks? - Yeah.
里面的所有东西都是我们今晚要用的道具
Everything in there is a prop we'll need for tonight.
爸爸
地铁日报
世界末日
及时做爱
所有宝贝
Everything.
接下来要这样做
All right, here's how this is going down.
你带着这个耳机和话筒
You'll be wearing this earpiece and microphone.
我会守在这里  告诉你该说什么
I'll be staked out here, telling you exactly what to say,
所以你只要集中精神就好了
so just stay focused and you'll be fine.
我们要先耍哪一出呢
Which play are we gonna run first?
"巴尼家的周末"怎么样
How about the "Weekend at Barney's"?
泰德  你第一天到美发沙龙上班
Oh, Ted, your first day at the salon,
就想给客人剪染一条龙服务吗
and you want to do a cut and color?
不  今晚我们将从这章开始
No. Tonight we're gonna start off with...
特别专递
冰人呼叫聂鲁达
Ice Man to Neruda.
10点钟方向有妖怪
Bogey at 10:00,
她装配有两台完全可操作的
and she is packing two fully-operational
毛衫拉伸机
sweater stretchers.
也就是简称为BOOBS[咪咪]的神器
That's bravo, Oscar, Oscar, bravo, Sierra.
估计有D罩杯
Possible delta cups.
收到  确定目标
Copy that. Engaging target.
完了
Over.
打扰了  我有一份给丽莎的快递
Excuse me, I have a delivery for Lisa.
-你是丽莎吗  -你是丽莎吗
- Are you Lisa? - Are you Lisa?
不是
Uh, no.
可是应该就是你啊
But you must be.
有人让我
I was told to...
把这个包裹给一个叫丽莎的女孩
...deliver this package to a girl named Lisa,
我可以不费力就认出她
and that I'd recognize her because she'd be...
因为她是酒吧里最漂亮的女孩
The most beautiful girl in this bar.
给  你的包裹   丽莎
So, here's your delivery, lisa.
我真不是丽莎
Uh, I am definitely not Lisa,
不过我很乐意帮你找到她
but I would be happy to help you find her.
很好  等会儿也许...
Great, and then maybe later...
我可以给你一个新的包裹  我的老二
I could give you a different package-- my penis.
这台词真是糟透了
That is a terrible line!
你说的方式错了
You said it wrong.
我没说错
I did not say it wrong.
我的老二
My penis.
-不对  -我的老二
- No. - My penis.
语气还是不对
Still not right.
我的老二  我的老二  我的老二
My penis, my penis, my penis!
大家好
Hello.
太不爽了
This sucks.
我无法接近斯特里克兰
I can't get near Strickland.
至少马修玩得挺开心
At least Marshall's having a good time.
他总是能找对话题跟别人聊
Man, he always knows just the right thing to say.
作为一个同性恋  安迪・沃霍尔当然喜欢瓶瓶罐罐
For a gay guy, Andy Warhol sure liked cans.
20世纪艺术界最有名的人物之一
将浓汤罐头与可乐瓶化身成艺术品
太失败了
This sucks.
也许我的魅力已不如从前
Maybe I've lost my charm.
不  马修
No, Marshall,
如果莉莉能在这个艺术殿堂里游刃有余
if Lily's gonna make it in this fancy art world,
你也能做到  振作起来
you're gonna have to make it, too, so suck it up,
别坐在艺术品上
stop sitting on the art,
秀出最好的自己
and bust out the "A" material.
你俩继续这样多干几杯
You two keep chugging like that,
你们就要
you're gonna have to
文森特・梵[去]厕所了  对吧
Vincent van go to the bathroom, am I right?
人家叫文森特・梵高
It's pronounced van Gogh.
去你的高
Oh, "Blogh" Me.
捐肾
我还是不明白  为什么出院之前
I still don't get why someone would leave the hospital
不换衣服呢  完毕
without changing into their clothes first. Over.
泰德  这是我的招
Ted, this is my thing.
就...  行吗
So just... okay?
完毕
Over.
行吗  完毕
Okay? Over.
你没事吧
Are you all right?
什么
What? Oh.
我没事  没事
Yes, yes, I'm fine.
明天  我...
Tomorrow, I'm...
要捐一个肾给我的好朋友
donating a kidney to my best friend.
我的挚友  巴尼
My best friend Barney.
不是马修
Not Marshall.
是巴尼
Barney.
马修弱爆了
Marshall's so lame.
总之...
Anyway, uh...
我只想最后再喝一杯  以防...
just wanted to grab one last drink, in case...
我没挺过来
you know, I don't make it.
你真勇敢
You are so brave.
听我说
Hey, listen.
在捐赠我这个器官之前  不如...
Before I give my best friend this organ, how about...
不行
Nope.
不  我不会那么说
Nope, I'm not saying that.
我听到了
I did hear you,
不过我不会说
but I'm not saying that.
因为我不会说
Because I'm not.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
等等  我知道你倾注了很多心血
One second. I know you put a lot of work into this.
我明白
I understand that.
我为什么不能和她聊聊天
Why can't I just talk to her?
可能会擦出什么火花呢
Maybe we'll hit it off...
好吧
Fine.
收到
Copy that.
不如我把另一个器官给你
How about I give you a different organ?
我的老二
My penis.
-你说的方式错了  -我没有说错
- You said it wrong. - I did not say it wrong!
感谢大家的光临
Thank you all so much for coming.
如果大家允许的话
If you'll indulge me,
我想给大家讲个关于
I would like to share a story
我过世的祖母的故事
about my dearly departed grandmother.
天啊
Oh, God.
告诉你个新闻  强尼・阿斯科特
News flash, Johnny Ascot:
很多人的祖母都过世了
Lots of people have dead grandmas.
不  马修
No, Marshall.
别这么尖酸
Don't be bitter.
你是为了莉莉来的
You're here for Lily.
看看她  那么专业
Just look at her, so professional.
她可还没坐过一件艺术品呢
She hasn't sat on a single piece of art.
为了莉莉  你得有风度地忍着
You're gonna ride this thing out with dignity for Lily.
不能再做让她尴尬的事情
Not one more thing that might embarrass her.
我就站在这里
I will simply stand here.
完全隐形
Perfectly invisible.
所有  我把这场展览
And so I dedicate this show
献给我的祖母
to my grandmother's memory.
现在
Now...
为了纪念她  请和我一起
please join me in honoring her
静默一分钟
with 60 seconds of absolute silence.
我有一个宠物叫尼斯湖水怪
好啦  聂鲁达  这场戏非常复杂
Okay, Neruda, this play is extremely complicated.
我猜  是要我用苏格兰口音
Let me guess. Does it involve me
说出"我的老二"吗
saying "My penis" in a Scottish accent?
渐入佳境啊  小伙子[苏格兰口音]
Now you're gettin' it, laddie!
罗宾  你来干嘛呢
Robin. What are you doing here?
我只是好奇你有没有
I was curious as to whether
给泰德找到女伴参加我们的婚礼
you found Ted a date to our wedding
找一个不这么...像魔鬼的女伴
who was a little less, you know, antichrist-y.
那是《泡妞秘笈》吗
Is that the Playbook?
不是  罗宾  那是沙发
No, Robin, that is a couch.
你是说沙发上的《泡妞秘笈》吗
Oh, you mean the Playbook on the couch?
-我可以解释  -不用了
- I can explain. - Don't bother.
我能...  泰德
I can ex... Uh, Ted? Uh...
我得离开指挥中心一下
I got to step away from mission control for a sec.
我走了之后  不要做任何傻事
Don't do anything stupid while I'm gone.
罗宾
Robin...
罗宾  等等
Robin, wait.
糟糕  我还没想好
Um... shoot. I haven't figured out
要说什么  你继续走
what I'm gonna say yet. Keep going.
罗宾  等等
Robin, wait.
很抱歉  我还留着《泡妞秘笈》
Look, I'm sorry that I still have the Playbook.
可是那本书包含了我一生的好点子
It's just, it's filled with a lifetime of great ideas.
我应该把这些心血都扔了吗
Am I supposed to just leave all that behind?
-是的  -但是...
- Yes. - But...
"巴尼家的周末"
"Weekend at Barney's"!
那是什么
Okay, what is that?
给我解释一下"巴尼家的周末"
Explain the "Weekend at Barney's" to me.
这还用解释吗
What's to explain?
我假扮死人
I play a dead guy,
泰德和马修拉我到处转悠
and Ted and Marshall carry me around.
好吧  凭这点  就有女人想和你上床
Okay. And based on that, girls want to sleep with you.
-超成功的  -但你死了
- Big time. - But you're dead.
对  但显然不是真死了
Yeah. Except not really, obviously.
但你泡的妞以为你死了
But the girl thinks you're dead.
不  她以为我活着
No, she thinks I'm alive.
-你本来就活着  -对
- Which you are. - Exactly.
-除了你死了  -对
- Except you're dead. - Exactly.
-只是你活着  -对
- Except you're alive. - Exactly.
好吧  与其一个大活人
Okay, so instead of... of being an alive person
假扮一个死人
pretending to be a dead person
假扮的活人
pretending to be an alive person,
为什么不就做个活人呢
why not just be an alive person?
好吧  我们从头说起
Okay, let's start from the beginning.
电影名叫《伯尼家的周末》
The movie is called Weekend at Bernie's.
而我叫巴尼
My name is Barney.
真是太对不起了  亲爱的
I'm so sorry, sweetie.
不知道你听到没
I don't know if you heard,
我掉了些彩虹糖豆
but I dropped some Skittles.
我还是回家算了  以免闯更大的祸
Do you know what, I'm just gonna go home before I make things worse.
你哪里都别去
You're not going anywhere.
我们是团队
We're a team.
我在你的法学院毕业典礼上露点
You stuck by me after my nip slip
是你掩护我
at your law school graduation.
我在巨人银行圣诞派对上露点  也是你掩护我
And after my nip slip at the GNB Christmas party.
还有那次我在
And after my nip slip
霍尼韦尔和库茨公司的家庭同乐日上露点
at the Honeywell and Coots Family Fun Day.
我不明白你为什么总是穿那件上衣
I don't know why you keep wearing that top.
好吧  我不走
All right, I'll stay put,
但我就此闭嘴
but I'm keeping my mouth shut.
不再讲笑话  不再吃糖
No more jokes, no more candy,
不再说什么忍者神龟
no more Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles.
你们在说忍者神龟吗
Hey, are you guys talking Ninja Turtles?
我是忍者神龟的铁杆粉丝
I'm a huge TMNT fan.
我是看着忍者神龟的漫画长大的
I grew up on those comic books.
我也是  我可着迷了
Me, too! I was obsessed.
你知道原稿漫画是在1984年
Did you know that the original comic debuted
新罕布什尔的动漫大会上首次展出的吗
in 1984 at a convention in New Hampshire?
知道
Uh, yes.
你知道漫画的两位作者总是对
Did you know that Eastman and Laird always had their doubts
自己创作的人物被商业化有疑虑吗
about their characters being commercialized?
知道
Yes!
你知道后面墙上的画
Did you know that the painting on the back wall
灵感来源于斯普林特老师吗[忍者神龟角色]
is inspired by Master Splinter?
耗子玩空手道那幅啊
Oh, the one of the rat doing karate.
我现在明白了
I see it now.
我是斯特里克兰
Hey, I'm Strickland.
你好  我是马修
Hey. Marshall.
这是我妻子  莉莉  事实上
And this is my wife, Lily, who, as a matter of fact,
她是纽约最大的艺术品收藏家之一的
happens to represent one of the biggest art collectors
私人代理
in New York City.
我喜爱你的作品
I love your work.
看到你得到认可  真是可喜可贺
It's great to see you getting some recognition.
谢谢  一切来之不易
Thank you. It's been a long haul.
第一幅画卖的钱
The first painting I ever sold,
我用来修车
I used the money to get my car fixed.
你可以说
You might say...
我用钱让车走[音近梵高]
I used it to make my van go.
你知道有一种事叫死后僵"硬"吗
Um, a little something called rigor mortis?
别这样
Oh, come on.
为了一本书你至于气成这样吗
Are you really this mad about a book?
你真以为我只是气这本书吗  巴尼
You really think that this is just about a book, Barney?
你骗了我
You lied to me.
如果我们要结婚
If we're gonna be in a marriage
要彼此信任  那你永远也不能对我说谎
and trust each other, you can't lie to me ever.
真的吗
Really?
这真是太好了
Well, that's just great.
不知你注意到没有  过去八年
Because, in case you haven't noticed these last eight years,
说谎是我的最强项
lying is what I do best.
我是个魔术师  罗宾
I'm a magician, Robin.
误导与欺骗是我的惯用伎俩
Misdirection and deceit are my stock in trade.
你不要我对你说谎
You don't want me to lie to you?
谎言是我们在一起的原因
Lies are the reason that we're together.
我做的每一件事
Everything single thing I did
令你在屋顶上答应求婚的每一件事
to get you to say yes to me on that rooftop--
帕特里斯  假订婚  每一件事
Patrice, the false engagement, everything--
全都是谎言
it was all utter malarkey.
但是
But...
在这些谎言之下
underneath all of those lies
有一个事实
is one true thing.
这个事实可以支撑
One true thing that can support the weight
全世界的谎言
of all the lies in the world, and...
这个事实就是我爱你
and that's the fact that I love you.
你知道我说这话时
And you know that when I say that...
我没有说谎
I am not lying.
你刚刚又解开我的胸罩了吗
Did you just unhook my bra again?
珍妮特  这真是太好了
Jeanette, this is great.
我们复合了
We're back together.
你会参加巴尼与罗宾的婚礼
You're coming to Barney and Robin's wedding.
我找到了两个你没有摔碎的酒杯
I found two wine glasses you didn't smash.
你可以说我疯了  但我有预感
Call me crazy, but I've got a feeling,
从现在开始  我们的生活只有蔚蓝的天空...
from here on out, it's gonna be nothing but blue skies and...
这个  他妈的
What... the hell...
是什么
is this?!
你看这条泰德发来的短信
Check out this text from Ted.
我的天  这到底是怎么回事
Oh, my... What the hell happened here?
珍妮特和我小吵了一架
Jeanette and I had a little spat.
要来点红酒吗
Would anyone like some wine?
这是好酒  产地是罗讷河谷
It's a nice Cotes du Rhne.
不过需要倒出来醒一下酒
Still needs to breathe a bit.
知道吗  我楼上有醒酒杯
You know what? I got a decanter upstairs, so...
就这么喝吧
We should just drink it now.
最后的压轴戏
And for the grand finale,
我找到了你的烟火
I found your fireworks.
看看烟火会把你的宝贝《泡妞秘籍》怎么样
Let's see what they do to your precious Playbook!
不  珍妮特  别这样
No! Jeanette, please,
那是巴尼毕生的心血之作
that's Barney's life's work!
没事  泰德
It's fine, Ted.
炸了吧  珍妮特
Blow it up, Jeanette.
好了
Okay.
再也不谈恋爱了
No more dating.
我已经准备好安定下来
I'm ready to settle down.
孩子们
And, kids...
我这辈子第一次发自肺腑地
for the first time in my life,
说出这句话
I really meant it.
我的靴子
Oh... The boots...